

AVINASH DHUMAL

Engineering Manager

CONTACT INFO



+91-779-840-6759



avinash.dhumal@hotmail.com



Pune, MH, India

ONLINE PRESENCE



LinkedIn Profile



Online Profile



medium.com blog



Hacker Rank Profile

ABOUT ME

Experienced **Technical People Manager** with **13+ years** in software **management**, **architecture**, **design**, **development**, **and support**. Led and managed client, database, and enterprise applications using the **Microsoft Technology** stack in both **Azure and AWS** Cloud environments.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (Last 3)

Engineering Manager



R1 RCM, Inc. | FEB 2023 - PRESENT

- Orchestrated and managed two dynamic Scrum teams, forming over 16+
 members, to develop two critical healthcare products.
- Led an initiative to reduce manual touch for operators during patient
 appointment, resulting in a cost reduction of \$550,000 and an improved
 patient experience.
- Streamlined post-discharge workflows by centralizing patient information, saving \$100,000 in costs.
- Successfully migrated the Patient Communication Platform to Genesys
 PureCloud using Azure cloud and .NET Core technologies, delivering
 \$270,000 in added value.
- Functioned as a bridge between technology and business, aligning technical solutions with overarching business goals and strategies for success.
- Pioneering performance, code reviews, mentoring programs, and ongoing guidance to nurture a high-performing team, promoting professional growth, and fostering a culture of continuous improvement.
- Demonstrating effective resource allocation and budget management,
 perfecting resource use to consistently deliver projects on time and within budget constraints.

Technical Associate Manager





- Achieved significant cost savings of over \$1M+ by efficiently managing and migrating applications and data from on-premises environments to the AWS Cloud platform across more than 20 countries.
- Spearheaded Tier3 and DLA product operations and automation initiatives
 on a global scale.
- Architected the PBots Self Service portal, a transformative solution for automating operational activities.
- Led the development of the T3Online product using agile methodologies, fostering a collaborative and adaptable environment for successful product delivery.
- Consistently improved security (vulnerability) with a remarkable reduction in the Rapid 7 security score from 10+ to 1+.
- Skilfully managed and mentored a team of 11 engineers (direct), overseeing their performance, growth, and development.

SKILLS

TECHNOLOGIES

TOOLS

.NET MVC .NET Core C# **VB.NET** Windows Web API SQL Server Services WCF Web HTML5 / Bootstrap Services CSS3 Design jQuery Angular JS Angular TypeScript Vue JS

TFS	GitLab	Jira	Azure DevOps
Service Now	Remedy	Pager Duty	Jenkins
MS Projects	MS Visio	Wireframe Sketcher	Lucid Charts
Checkmarks	Confluence	X-Ray	Postman

CLOUD PL	ATFORMS —	
Azure	AWS	Cloud Migration

LEADERSHIP & MANAGEMENT

Team	Mentoring/Coaching	Conflict	Decision
Leader		Mgmt.	Making
Problem	Product Mgmt.	Project	Risk
Solving		Mgmt.	Mgmt.
Resource Mgmt.	Technical Expertise		

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (Last 3)

Technical Assistant Manager

FLEX | JUN 2015 - FEB 2020



- Accomplished 3 major software releases and over 50 successful sprints in a
 5-year tenure, demonstrating consistent delivery excellence.
- Led and optimized automated order processing (EDI) operations,
 contributing to a substantial revenue stream of approximately \$10 million.
- Orchestrated a pivotal major release in FY 2018-19 for procurement department, resulting in an impressive ROI surpassing \$110 million, highlighting strategic leadership and financial acumen.
- Excelled as a Scrum Master, overseeing a proficient team of 6 direct reports,
 driving Agile projects using Azure DevOps, and excelling in KRA
 management, annual goal setting, and performance appraisals.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering - I.T.

Pune University

JULY 2010

65.13 %

Diploma - I.T.

MSBTE, Mumbai

JUNE 2007

70.17 %

S. S. C.

Pune Vidyapeeth

JUNE 2004

72.80 %

AWARDS

Ö	Excellence Award		
X	R1 RCM, Inc.		



Ace Award
Pitney Bowes, Inc.

Star Award
Pitney Bowes, Inc.

Gateway – The leaders League

Titanium Award

Platinum Award flex

Spot Award
L&T Infotech

Ace Award
Hexaware Technologies

To view my full accomplishments – more than decade + professional experience, <u>click here</u> to view my online portfolio.